<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>academia on Thoughts About Crime Data and Research</title>
    <link>/tags/academia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in academia on Thoughts About Crime Data and Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/academia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Correlation is causation</title>
      <link>/year/06/07/correlation-is-causation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/year/06/07/correlation-is-causation/</guid>
      <description>One of the most common tropes when talking about research is that “correlation isn’t causation.” This is generally used in opposition of the research at hand. Don’t like the findings? You can just say that correlation isn’t causation and dismiss it.1 Academics also like to use this phrase defensively about their own research. If they do a correlational study and find something they don’t like (say, that X policy they support is related to more crime) they can say that it’s only a correlational study so policy changes should wait until further research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most code you write for research is a waste of time (because someone else has already done it)</title>
      <link>/year/05/02/most-code-you-write-for-research-is-a-waste-of-time-because-someone-else-has-already-done-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/year/05/02/most-code-you-write-for-research-is-a-waste-of-time-because-someone-else-has-already-done-it/</guid>
      <description>It is very rare in criminology research to use quantitative data that no one has ever used before.1 It does happen. Primarily in surveys that the authors wrote themselves - including modifying past surveys - but also through collecting administrative data yourselves such as through data sharing agreements or FOIA requests. The majority of papers, however, rely on data the other people have used before. Often thousands of times before since many criminology papers use publicly available administrative data from government agencies such as the FBI, BJS, or local police departments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIBRS is a looming problem for criminology, not just for crime data</title>
      <link>/year/05/01/nibrs-is-a-looming-problem-for-criminology-not-just-for-crime-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/year/05/01/nibrs-is-a-looming-problem-for-criminology-not-just-for-crime-data/</guid>
      <description>Last year marked the first year that the FBI stopped collecting Uniform Crime Reporting (UCR) data and only took National Incident-Based Reporting System (NIBRS) data from police agencies. Now, 16 months after they started collecting data we still have another 6 or 7 months to wait until they release the data, as the FBI normally releases NIBRS in October or November of the year following the data collection. NIBRS data has been around since 1991 so criminologists have had over 30 years to prepare for using NIBRS data instead of relying on UCR data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Saying No</title>
      <link>/year/04/24/on-saying-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/year/04/24/on-saying-no/</guid>
      <description>Why say noAcademia is built on uncertainty. This is most clearly evident in how our currency of published papers are evaluated - through anonymous reviewers that in many cases want different things from your paper which means that you may spend equal time writing the paper as revising it for the whims of reviewers, often in areas that don’t actually address the core of the paper.1 But the most serious avenue of uncertainty for academics, and the least visible, is that you never know what you have to do to achieve your career goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>READI Chicago and Press Release Research</title>
      <link>/year/04/24/readi-chicago-and-inconvenient-null-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/year/04/24/readi-chicago-and-inconvenient-null-results/</guid>
      <description>Recently the Chicago Crime Lab released a report about the effect of READI Chicago, an intervention that attempts to reduce gun violence by focusing on people at the highest likelihood of being the victim or perpetrator of such violence. Participants in this program are given an 18-month subsidized job and cognitive behavioral programming. The program costs about $60,000 per participant for a 20-month period so is a costly program.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
