<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Thoughts About Crime Data and Research</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Thoughts About Crime Data and Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NIBRS is a looming problem for criminology, not just for crime data</title>
      <link>/year/05/01/nibrs-is-a-looming-problem-for-criminology-not-just-for-crime-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/year/05/01/nibrs-is-a-looming-problem-for-criminology-not-just-for-crime-data/</guid>
      <description>Last year marked the first year that the FBI stopped collecting Uniform Crime Reporting (UCR) data and only took National Incident-Based Reporting System (NIBRS) data from police agencies. Now, 16 months after they started collecting data we still have another 6 or 7 months to wait until they release the data, as the FBI normally releases NIBRS in October or November of the year following the data collection. NIBRS data has been around since 1991 so criminologists have had over 30 years to prepare for using NIBRS data instead of relying on UCR data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>READI Chicago and Press Release Research</title>
      <link>/year/04/24/readi-chicago-and-inconvenient-null-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/year/04/24/readi-chicago-and-inconvenient-null-results/</guid>
      <description>Recently the Chicago Crime Lab released a report about the effect of READI Chicago, an intervention that attempts to reduce gun violence by focusing on people at the highest likelihood of being the victim or perpetrator of such violence. Participants in this program are given an 18-month subsidized job and cognitive behavioral programming. The program costs about $60,000 per participant for a 20-month period so is a costly program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coming of the (Carjacking) Superpredator</title>
      <link>/year/04/23/carjackings-from-nibrs-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/year/04/23/carjackings-from-nibrs-data/</guid>
      <description>In 1995 John DiLulio, then a politics professor at Princeton, published in article in the Weekly Standard about the coming wave of superpredators. These superpredators were essentially evil children who did nothing but commit serious crime. In his own words: “on the horizon, therefore, are tens of thousands of severely morally impoverished juvenile super-predators. They are perfectly capable of committing the most heinous acts of physical violence for the most trivial reasons (for example, a perception of slight disrespect or the accident of being in their path.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
